A
Speaker 1: lot of exciting things happening, huh?
Nah, not really. What's the
Speaker 1: latest? Trump said something. He had an interview and he said something, right?
He was
Speaker 2: speaking at the
Speaker 3: opening or the construction site for the new flagpoles that he's installing at the White House. Here,
you know
Speaker 4: what happened at the New York Times. Let me pick it up.
Speaker 5: He was asked about whether he was going to join the strike zone.
Speaker 6: He
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): said, maybe I will, maybe I won't, which is about respect because he loves to maintain his element of surprise.
Speaker 8: It's so stupid. I mean, he's sitting there with these guys in these yellow
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): construction or whatever, these working man hats and their outfits. And he's like, oh, you all voted for Trump. The Federal Reserve, they're stupid. I should appoint myself. It's like such grotesque.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Such a grotesque
Speaker 10: display. He said he should appoint himself
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): as the chairman of the Federal Reserve. Yeah, he's like, maybe I should just appoint myself. I think he said something like, we have a stupid person there. Well, that's kind of funny. It
is kind
Speaker 11: of funny. The
Speaker 12: thing with Trump that I've never found it difficult to readily acknowledge is that he continues to be amusing from a pure entertainment standpoint.
Speaker 13: yeah it sort of gets i don't know is it getting old it gets a little bit
Speaker 14: old it's old but like i just chuckled at the idea that he would say that he would install
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): himself as the chairman of the federal reserve the the funny thing was the um what was the funny well i mean it's kind of it's also like getting kind of dark because they're asking like did you you know when biden got cancer i was surprised by his
Speaker 8: response did you see this well
his initial
Speaker 15: response was very formulaic
Speaker 15: Like the very first thing he said
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): was we wish President Biden and his family the best of it was
Speaker 17: like a tweet, right? It was like a truth. Yeah. But then when he was asked about it more extemporaneously, he basically said
Speaker 18: he doesn't
Speaker 19: care that Biden is cancer or something. Yeah.
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, and he bashes him about the Minnesota shooting. He says, I'm not going to talk
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): to Tim Walz. He starts insulting him. He says he's a loser or he's a sick
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): guy or something like that. He wasn't always this kind of mean-spirited. I don't think that would have been Trump like five or six or seven years
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): ago.
Speaker 12: Um...
Speaker 12: well during the first term he constantly would bring up hillary clinton's emails and things just just as a foil so he would be demonizing at every opportunity hillary
clinton or
Speaker 12: obama obviously i think
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): that's accelerated to some extent or as you suggest
gotten a
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): bit more vicious and personal just because he views
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): biden not only as like the political
opponents,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): he can use as a scapegoat, which many politicians do to some degree, Trump a bit more theatrically, but he sees Biden as the
leader of the regime that was
Speaker 18: trying to put him in prison.
Yeah, I
Speaker 25: guess that's right. Yeah, I guess that kind of added to the bitterness. Which is not
Speaker 18: entirely
Speaker 26: wrong, but maybe it's not exactly how Trump imagines it, but there's a kernel of truth there.
Speaker 26: I mean, there's not really a kernel
Speaker 8: of truth there because Biden himself... Well,
Speaker 27: the Biden Department of Justice, not... Well, the Biden Department of Justice, but Biden was not micromanaging.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): He appointed Merrick Garland, and there's no evidence he said, Merrick Garland, you have to prosecute Trump or anything like
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): that. Biden, I mean, there's a New York Times article from 2021 in which Biden essentially conveyed, indirectly, of course, he's not like Trump where he's going to put out a tweet ordering his attorney general to do something, but signals were clearly sent
Speaker 17: that conveyances were clearly made that biden favored well maybe prosecuting trump over january 6th signals well and then
Speaker 29: the other thing it was one step what did the
Speaker 30: entire like democratic apparatus want trump to be prosecuted over it but it was one step removed on top of that it wasn't even garland it
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): was an independent council so like you have these steps like
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): biden may be conveyed to garland which is not enforceable in any way it doesn't guarantee anything and then garland appoints an uh independent prosecutor and that's how you get the prosecution so it's very kind
of
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): uh, tenuously
Speaker 12: divided. Nonetheless, it's true that the Biden DOJ, to the extent that we, we use that nomenclature prosecuted Trump.
Speaker 33: Yeah, that's true. Okay. Well, that's like
Speaker 34: maybe that's appointed as independent counsel, Jack Smith, who was this semi fanatical
Speaker 12: international law zealot for literally from the Hague at, at the, uh,
at
Speaker 12: the
Speaker 26: International Criminal Court. Okay. What does that make him? Why does that make him a salad?
Speaker 14: Well, it shows that there
was like
Speaker 14: an ideological valence
to whom
Speaker 35: Garland appointed to oversee these Trump prosecutions
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): that suggested it wasn't just going to be within the narrow confines of ordinary criminal law.
Speaker 13: Well, anyways, okay, well, that's
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): a side discussion. Anyway, this Iran thing, where do you see this going? Do you think, does it look like Trump is going to hit them?
Well, I mean, he's
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): telegraphing it.
Think
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): what happened the first day that the operation was launched. He deemingly engaged in public disinformation. I know that term gets overused.
Speaker 37: Yeah.
Speaker 12: And it's used to collapse a whole array of stuff into one
system.
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): category, including sometimes political speech on somewhat spurious grounds, but for Trump to have put out a post three hours before the operation was launched or even less saying I've directed my entire
Speaker 34: administration to focus on achieving a diplomatic resolution to the Iran situation and we're committed to diplomacy, et cetera, et cetera.
at which
Speaker 12: point he must have known if he had any foreknowledge at all that
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): the bombing campaign was
about to
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): be initiated and that public disinformation
Speaker 12: in a classical sense. And so everything
that he's
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): been saying or that the administration has been saying ever since needs to be seen through that prism
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): And there's
Speaker 12: a lot of evidence of an acceleration of U.S. military assets in the region, tanker,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): aircraft positioned, et cetera. And I think maybe the most dispositive factor is that Fox News seems very much in favor of joining the Israeli operation. And that's what Trump is principally influenced by. I was I I don't usually watch the five.
a
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): 5 p.m. chat show. But I've been looking at it lately just to get a sense of what they're saying because it's very likely that Trump would be watching
it or
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): similar shows. And they acknowledge,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): or at least they gesture at the fact that there is some debate within MAGA or the America First movement about whether bombing Iran is America First. But they invariably come up.
with
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): a rationale for why it is, in fact, America first to bomb
Speaker 26: around and do regime change. So they're trying to deny that this is a regime change operation, I guess. It
seems like
Speaker 1: what you're saying from Fox is that they want the U.S.
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): involved, but they
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): want to worship Trump more than... So they'll call Trump brilliant no matter what. They have a slight preference for war, but the real preference
Speaker 42: is kissing up to Trump. Yeah,
Speaker 43: yeah. I mean, what they...
Speaker 43: But what's seemingly going on is they're surmising
Speaker 17: that Trump is wanting to get involved. And so they then have to reason backwards from that to explain how it works.
Speaker 45: I mean, it's interesting which way it's going. Yeah, it's kind of going in both directions. It's like Trump kind
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): of... Well, what
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): was it like when Israel started striking and then Trump was a little bit distant from it? Yeah, I wonder what
Speaker 12: that one or two days was. It was just that bogus Rubio statement that people...
Speaker 12: The first statement from the administration after the campaign was launched was that kind of cursory written statement that was put out.
Speaker 47: Yeah, no, but it's not just nothing.
Speaker 48: It's not cursory. It's not completely pro forma. It's like we had nothing to, it was basically we had nothing to do with it. Well, it was
Speaker 12: perfectly worded. It didn't necessarily mean that there was no facilitation or coordination. In fact, it strongly implied that that was the
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): case if you have any.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): background knowledge of how u.s israeli relations function it simply communicated that the u.s maybe was not like directly kinetically involved in the initial phase of offensive operations
didn't mean that there
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): was no quote involvement i don't think that the u.s israeli intelligence sharing apparatus was at
Speaker 33: all well i mean it was kind of like if that that's the statement you would expect if the trial,
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): you know, I believe the reporting, it makes sense.
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): that Trump basically was just watching and would love to take credit if it goes well. And that's basically it. I think Netanyahu is smart, and I think Netanyahu has kind of played him pretty well. Trump, to an extent, wanted to be played. It's not like he's very, you know, it's not like he's pro-Iran or anything like that. But it is like kind of, you know, I think the Israelis know that just because of
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): the nature of Trump's coalition. If...
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): Like, if Israel actually ever gets really in trouble, if, like, somehow, I don't know, Iran is, like, surprised we have a nuke, or, you know, they have enough things,
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): they make, you know, life in Israel very, very hard. Like, they know in the end that the Trump administration is going to be held about, right? I think Netanyahu can keep pushing, and he knows he can keep pushing. Trump might like it, he might not like it.
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): But in
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): the end, like, he's going to come back and he's going to be on his side just because of Trump's instincts and because of the way the Republicans are.
I'm just not buying
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): this narrative that Trump was in any way meaningfully, quote, played by Netanyahu. Yes, Netanyahu is a Safiyah, your operator. When he first came to be a prime minister in the 1990s,
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): actually, he was hailed, Netanyahu was, as the first American prime minister of Israel, kind of as a semi-joke, but just referring to the fact that
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): He spent his formative years in the United States. He went to high school in Pennsylvania, et cetera.
He
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): obviously has a very comprehensive understanding of the nuances and subtleties of American politics.
And so, yes, he
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): understands the nature of the Trump coalition and how to phrase things or frame things in
public and
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): probably also in private. However,
the idea
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): that Trump was just unwillingly dragged into it, to me, just doesn't pass the smell test. Trump said in an interview with Time magazine in April, he was asked about the prospect of bombing Iran with Israel. And
he
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): said, I'm
not going
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): to get dragged into it. And the reporter was like, oh, really? So you're not going to...
And he
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): said, no, it's that I'm not I'm not going to get dragged into it. I'm going to go in voluntarily and enthusiastically and I'm going to lead
Speaker 14: the pack.
So I'm sure he
Speaker 14: probably said,
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): did he not say if they you know, if they don't negotiate, if we don't come to a group, it's always like, you know, you're fine. You seem to believe strongly in like Trump's
Speaker 49: consistency.
much
Speaker 49: more than a lot of other people.
Speaker 34: It's more in his agency. And yeah, there was consistency in how these so-called negotiations were structured. Yeah, it was weird. Such a way that they were doomed to fail almost by design. I don't know if Trump had consciously
Speaker 14: in his head the explicit intention that he was going to structure the negotiations that he, for some reason, delegated singularly to his catch-all envoy, Witkoff.
I don't
Speaker 14: know if Trump, like if there was a flash of a thought inside his brain somewhere saying, oh, I want these to fail so we can then join a Israeli operation. But they were structured in a way that made
Speaker 51: that inevitable because Iran was never going to be able to accede to the fundamental U.S.
Speaker 52: demand to essentially inflict on itself a huge national humiliation and forfeiture of sovereignty. So like, what are we supposed to infer? So
Speaker 53: explain
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): this because this is the interesting part because they had this JCPOA.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): which
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): let Iran enrich some kind of uranium within Iran, right? And
then the Trump
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): administration wanted something, their initial demand was something more extreme than... Initial demand,
Speaker 12: it's not as though they put out a formal policy paper spelling out what their official demands were. It's always hazy, just like it always is with Trump, especially if you're just going to outsource the negotiations,
Speaker 54: seemingly, to Steve Witkoff, who's a New York real estate guy...
Who
Speaker 54: happened to be on the golf
Speaker 30: course. But isn't Whitcoff understood as a dumb? This is kind of weird. Whitcoff in the reporting is understood as like a more dumbish guy.
And I
Speaker 30: don't buy that. I mean,
I
Speaker 43: think that's part of the facade.
Whitcoff
Speaker 12: has been a huge pro-Israel guy. You know, he's going out to these pro-Israel galas. Literally the night before the Israeli operation was launched, he was speaking at some fundraiser with Miriam Adelson. Oh, really?
uh
Speaker 12: for united hat salah which is like this uh orthodox uh ultra orthodox aid organization in israel and
he was saying
Speaker 12: iran nuclear nuclear iran is an existential threat
Speaker 51: the united states and israel must unite to combat this threat whatever the cost etc so yeah i mean a lot of these hagiographical profiles of
whitkoff that
Speaker 35: have been pumped out over the past few months depict him as i quote
dove
Speaker 35: and
Speaker 12: his diplomatic acumen has been praised. Oh,
Speaker 34: he's like the new Kissinger. He has all this unconventional thinking, and he's a breath of fresh air. He's not from the establishment, so maybe
Speaker 51: he really knows what he's doing. He's going to shake things up.
What has he
Speaker 51: accomplished? Every diplomatic portfolio that was delegated to him is dramatically worsened.
Speaker 56: What's going on
Speaker 51: with Hamas and Gaza? What's going on with Iran? It's all getting...
And
Speaker 51: worse, Iran, catastrophically
Speaker 57: so.
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. So do you think there's an Israel-Russia? What's your view of his role in the Russian negotiations? That's the place where I hear the context of he's a dove in these
Speaker 1: things. Is Russia and Israel different, or is he the same across these areas?
Speaker 58: Uh,
Speaker 34: well, I mean, I think I would maybe cosh against this oversimplified dub versus hawk
Speaker 12: framing. It is the case that Whitcoff. Okay. So compared to the Biden administration, it is dubbish to even engage in direct negotiations with Russia at all.
So we can
Speaker 12: stipulate that. And it is true that Whitcoff. after he had his
Speaker 12: succession of meetings with putin would come back and say you know
these four
Speaker 12: oblasts have
a majority or a
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): plurality or whatever it is of russian ethnics yeah
kind of gave
Speaker 60: some credence to potentially acquiescing to some of yeah and
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): i remember whitkoff had these weird things like where he would be like oh you know the one about putin giving trump like a portrait or something and then like the way whitkoff talks i don't know if this is reflective of negotiations
the way
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): he
Speaker 1: talks to Tucker yeah he
Speaker 61: I consider Putin a
Speaker 1: personal friend now or something like that. Yeah, yeah, he says this stuff, which is, you know, kind of odd.
Speaker 62: But that's all—I have understood that to just be Wyckoff musing. Like,
Speaker 43: what is—has that been connected to any policy change with respect to Russia? No, not really. Pete Hegseth last week was testifying before
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Congress, and—
Very few
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): people picked up on this, but of course, because I'm a brilliant genius, I picked up on it.
He was
Speaker 34: asked about the continuation of Ukraine arms provisions,
Speaker 12: and Biden,
in the
Speaker 12: month before he left office, did three rounds of presidential drawdown authority provisions to Ukraine, they're called, which amounted to several billion
dollars, so
Speaker 12: huge outweighs of arms to Ukraine. Yeah.
And
Speaker 12: those are still being dispersed by the Biden administration, by the Trump administration. As we speak, according to Hegsif, so like
Speaker 34: that fundamental element of the policy dynamic has not shifted, even if Whitcoff can go on a podcast and muse.
Speaker 34: about how maybe Putin has certain
Speaker 63: that we can accommodate. So
who
Speaker 1: do you think? So somebody is,
so I
Speaker 1: think the part of the idea, intuition here behind this, is like Whitcoff
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): is not a blob guy. He's not a foreign policy expert. I think people assume you see like a guy who is like a real estate guy who's just Trump's buddy.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): Like, he's going to be, like, whatever, negotiate with Putin. Like, he's not going to have, like, this attachment to Ukrainian national sovereignty and Ukrainian territorial integrity. I think that's why people think this.
Speaker 64: True enough.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah.
But
Speaker 64: I just don't think it's not—it hasn't amounted to anything substantive yet.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. Well, I mean, I do think that they did. I mean, the idea that they didn't do anything on Russia that was different—like you said, they negotiated.
Speaker 65: You know, I think that they have these kind
of—
they
Speaker 65: floated these kind of negotiating
Speaker 66: for the sake of negotiating he did
Speaker 65: that no but they floated they floated these proposals that were giving more than biden would
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): have gave at the time right because there was like they would recognize was it they would recognize crimea even that was on the table which was never on the table with biden that was floated
Speaker 29: somebody it was it's never that's not
the
Speaker 12: official position anywhere
It's
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): been reported, isn't it? That's been reported that this was the deal that they gave them. There was something like recognize Crimea, freeze the lines, and then move on. That was basically the deal.
Speaker 65: And I think they realized that Putin wouldn't take it.
Speaker 66: It's been reported that recognition of Crimea was an official offer. I don't know about
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): official, but that's how you get to official. It's not like you send them DocuSign or something. It's like that's how you
talk and
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): that's
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): how you do these things. And I think what they found out was Putin wasn't.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): just interested in like freezing the line and so like there just was a there just was a disagreement like what Putin would take and what
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): the U.S. and Ukraine would take they just didn't match and that's all there was to it but we're willing to be selfish relative to
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): Biden there could be there there could be some significant I think a little bit overstated but still
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): significant differences with respect
to Ukraine
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Russia but on in the Middle East it's a whole different
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): story and that's what we're dealing with now yeah at a chlysmic eventuality
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): at least my perspective. Think
Speaker 34: about what do Wyckoff do?
Speaker 12: Remember, when Trump came into office, Wyckoff, on Trump's behalf, in conjunction with Brett McGurk, who was his counterpart in the outgoing Biden administration, came up
Speaker 63: with this supposed ceasefire in Gaza. And the idea was, oh,
You
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): know, I was being berated and hectored, including, you know, behind the scenes and also publicly by people who were offended that
Speaker 12: I wasn't sufficiently in awe of the fact that Trump really put the hammer down on Netanyahu and forced him to accept this ceasefire in Gaza.
And
Speaker 68: it did
Speaker 12: last for like a month and a
half or something. And
Speaker 43: then...
Speaker 43: Wyckoff was supposed to have been in charge of
Speaker 12: extending, at least nominally, the claim was initially that Wyckoff was going to be very deeply involved in getting to the second phase of the Gaza ceasefire, which is supposed to bring about a permanent end to the war. Instead, what they used that period for was to rearm Israel.
The
Speaker 12: Trump administration removed whatever limited constraints that the Biden administration had in place on the provision of heavy munitions to Israel. And they got out a bunch of hostages, which maybe
Speaker 43: placated some of the domestic discontent against Netanyahu within Israel. They made
Speaker 34: sure that they wanted to get out the remaining American-Israeli dual nationals. And...
Speaker 34: Then Trump greenlit the resumption of the Gaza campaign in mid-March, and it's still going on right now.
So
Speaker 69: where
Speaker 43: is this diplomatic genius? Where is the dovishness? In fact, this is all according to the plan that Netanyahu publicly stated when he said that he was going to accept this Trump ceasefire. He said, look, Trump assured us that he's going to accelerate arms to us and that the war is not going to end and we can
begin it once
Speaker 43: more at a time in place.
Speaker 43: And so that's the mindset around Israel-related issues in the sense to Iran. You asked about the enrichment thing. Yeah, the JCPOA under Obama, which, let's remember, was painstakingly negotiated on a multilateral basis for over two years, arguably even
Speaker 69: longer,
not
Speaker 43: just bilaterally between the U.S. and Iran, but with Russia, China, the EU, et cetera.
Speaker 43: It wasn't just like this ultimatum. It wasn't the
Speaker 1: EU, it was Germany, France, and the UK, I think.
The EU
Speaker 3: as an entity also had a... Was it? I believe so. Let me check.
Speaker 70: Yeah, I don't believe
Speaker 71: so. JCPOA, let me see
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): here.
Yeah, the
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): European Union did. The European Union is a signatory. P plus five.
Speaker 72: In addition to France, Germany, UK, on their own.
Speaker 72: Okay, well, they didn't negotiate. I think they just pro forma. Okay, whatever. Either
Speaker 12: way, it was multilateral, right? And it was a pretty laborious, drawn-out negotiation. And
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): the thing that they arrived at, that Iran could maintain uranium
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): enrichment at 3.67%, which was seen
to be
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): for civilian purposes, right? And then,
so
Speaker 3: Trump obviously
Speaker 12: withdraws.
And on the
Speaker 12: ground that, in part, it was intolerable to allow Iran to have any enrichment whatsoever. Yeah.
Speaker 75: And that was an interesting
Speaker 12: decision. The early phase of these negotiations went on TV. A lot of the restraint people who were always kind of, I mean, one thing that drives me crazy is that there's
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): this cadre of, I guess, right-leaning pundits and journalists who are always trying to interpret everything that the Trump administration does in the most charitable, restraint-oriented light.
so
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): they're always like grasping for whatever the most generous depiction they can find
Speaker 12: is of anything that they and that they're the ones
who are like
Speaker 12: hailing whitkoff as this uh diplomatic
master
Speaker 43: whitkoff went on they go on tv one time and like vaguely indicated that maybe it was possible that iran could have this 3.67 percent threshold and the
Speaker 12: very next day you might recall
you know
Speaker 12: there was an up you know there was an uproar among the genuinely hawkish people the very next day whitkoff puts out a statement on his official ex-government
Speaker 43: account saying let
me clarify in
Speaker 43: case anybody's confused iran can have no enrichment and then rubio trump and whitkoff
Speaker 34: proceeded to reiterate that position over and over again so my point is how if whitkoff is dovish
how is
Speaker 34: it that he was the
Yeah.
uh
Speaker 34: conveyor or the point person for a negotiation quote-unquote which could be very much reasonably seen as pure pretext by iran to give justification for the eventual bombing campaign because israel which they're saying and the u.s which
Speaker 51: they're saying can say that oh we tried to negotiate but iran was too intransigent and they weren't coming
to the table yeah yeah
So
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): I think there's a couple of things going on here. Yeah, that's right. And, you know, when you talk about Witkopf, I don't know his I don't know his connection to Adelson and his kind of Zionist,
Speaker 76: you know, Zionist leanings. I didn't know over the years. He hasn't been like he's not he's not a tabula rasa for defensive democracies or something
Speaker 43: where this has been his lifelong like ideological goal. But he said he's both been politically involved.
In
Speaker 43: Israel-related
Speaker 12: issues, this is the crowd that he's associating
Speaker 65: with. So it's kind of like, he's kind of like Kushner. He's not like a foreign policy expert, but he comes in with a strong tilt towards
Speaker 77: Israel, right?
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, Kushner's a good parallel, actually. I think he's probably the equivalent of a Kushner, and Kushner was also hardcore pro-Israel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah. So I think, yeah, so I think what's going on here is there's these, like, two tracks of, like, Iran—
Speaker 1: kind of
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): what's going on with Iran.
So I
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): think that like Ben Rhodes and like Obama types are most concerned with nuclear proliferation. So if all you care about is nuclear proliferation, I think you've got the deal that would prevent nuclear proliferation. I mean, I think everyone in the world, except basically Netanyahu and Trump, thought that this deal was working.
Speaker 35: Well, the entire Republican Party.
Yeah,
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): yeah, the Republicans and Netanyahu. Actually,
Speaker 35: the Democratic Party,
Speaker 79: like Schumer and Bob Menendez.
Yeah,
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): but then there were other people, and I think the Republicans and Nanyahu, I mean, they probably—who knows what they believe about nuclear proliferation. They do worry about it. But their
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): main concern is Iran. They clearly
Speaker 72: don't care that much about nuclear proliferation because they're not even signatories to the NPT. Well, no, I mean, Iranian nuclear proliferation,
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): obviously. But these people—
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): dislike the Iranian regime. So if Obama or Rhodes could have a world where Iran doesn't develop a nuke, but it's still in power, and it basically can do the same thing, said, well, it can support Hezbollah. Hezbollah's kind of life diet now, but it's kind of a sphere of influence. Remember Obama told Jeffrey Goldberg, I think, at some point that other people in the region will have to learn to live with Iran. The idea is you accept Iran as a local power. So that's
Speaker 14: why Obama was
Speaker 14: Oh, he's a secret Muslim. That's why he has this affinity for the Ayatollahs.
Speaker 4: Well, yeah, he was attacked for that before that, for the
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): bowing and all that other stuff. But then the – yeah, and so that's their perspective.
And
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): the perspective of Netanyahu and Republicans, I guess Ted Cruz and Trump maybe, is the idea that Iran is like the root of all evil. We
talk to
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): these people sometimes. I mean, they really do think like everything in the Middle East kind of goes through Iran. Iran is like the most evil regime in the world.
Speaker 81: Yeah.
Speaker 81: It's the head of the snake, or as Natal says, the head of the octopus. The cats settle on an animal analogy. And so
if
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): you want—that's your perspective. You'd keep trying to sabotage the nuclear negotiations, right? You
would
Speaker 76: keep saying you would make these impossible demands.
Speaker 43: That's the deal. And
so if
Speaker 43: there's a multilateral sustainable framework for Iran to continue enriching uranium at a civilian level—
Speaker 43: But the regime is intact and, in fact, somewhat even legitimized within
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): international structures. That's diametrically against what these people want. They want the overthrow of the regime itself. Yeah.
Speaker 65: So from that perspective, right. Okay, so that's where we are right now. And I think Trump, it was probably Witkoff or people around Witkoff.
You
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): know, he probably didn't like who got into Trump's idea in his head that like this was the red line. Like they could not they could not enrich any
Speaker 14: uranium within Iran. OK, and this is actually significant. Witt Hogg actually used the phrase red line. The red line is zero.
Speaker 43: And Republicans and Trump still have it in their folklore that Obama proved he was this huge weakling because he drew the red line in Syria.
and
Speaker 43: then did
Speaker 12: not bomb Assad quickly enough after the August 2013 chemical attack. So Trump has always been about, look, when
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): I draw a red line, I'm
really going
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): to enforce it.
Speaker 82: Okay. I missed this. You're right. This is a significant piece of information. All right. Yeah. So here
Speaker 83 (lower-pitched voice): I'm reading Reuters. A deal between U.S. and Iran must have been an agreement not to enrich uranium, what Whitcoff said on Sunday. And then he said, "Oh, it's cut off
Speaker 83 (lower-pitched voice): because Wordis has a paywall now. I have the clip somewhere of him saying it. It's okay, I can get the hell out of it. We don't need the clip, we can just read the words. We have a red line, and that is enrichment. We cannot allow
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): even 1% of enrichment capability, he told The Week. Okay, yeah, we don't have to listen to it. We got the words. Yeah, I
Speaker 85: wanted to find the exact quote. Yeah,
Speaker 43: yeah, he...
Speaker 43: Yeah, I think that's that's significant because Trump said Trump
Speaker 12: keeps Trump has this idea that if he puts out a red line because he wants to be tougher than Obama and then doesn't follow through, then he shows
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): himself to be. Yeah. And so this is
Speaker 86: interesting. So, yeah, it was kind of set up for. That's something like, oh, Ted Cruz and
Speaker 14: maybe Trump believe this. One thing I think people don't realize about Trump is that when he was first toying with the idea of getting into
Speaker 43: Republican politics.
Speaker 87: Mm-hmm.
in
Speaker 43: the early 2010s he picked a couple of issues that he
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): thought would resonate
one of them was obama's birth
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): certificate another was iran can't have a nuclear weapon and is evil like
he's been
Speaker 43: talking about iran somewhat randomly and
Speaker 43: inexplicably since around like 2011 when he was first trying to ingratiate himself to the Republican Party going to Tea Party events going to CPAC etc I actually saw Trump's first CPAC
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): speech believe it or not in 2000 I didn't pay it much mind unfortunately at the time but I did see it and Trump and Ted Cruz in September of 2015 jointly appeared even though they were putatively rivals at this point in the Republican primary they jointly appeared at a
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): party
Speaker 43: patriots rally at the Capitol in D.C. against the Iran deal.
So it
Speaker 43: really is a long statement on Trump's part, which is why it's so stupid that so many Trump voters who think that they're anti-war or think that they voted for Trump on anti-war grounds came out when this happened and said, oh, we've been betrayed. We're so shocked, et cetera, et cetera. We can't believe it. Trump promised peace in the Middle East because he went to Dearborn, Michigan and told - Yeah.
Speaker 43: Imams that he would bring, quote, peace as a vague platitude that wasn't connected to any policy outcome. Yeah, I mean, Trump, the administration now is correct. Trump has been unusually consistent on this issue. He
instituted a
Speaker 43: policy in his first term of extreme bellicosity toward Iran.
Speaker 43: withdrawing from JCPOA coming within 10 minutes. He said a bombing Iran in June of
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): 2019 because they shot down a U.S. drone over the Persian Gulf, not the Gulf of Mexico, the Persian Gulf, or sorry, the Gulf of America, the Persian Gulf, the maximum
Speaker 43: pressure policy, which is a regime change policy in a sense in that it's meant to impoverish and weaken and destabilize
Speaker 34: the regime such that a,
Speaker 34: overthrow could happen. Trump actually, when there were
Speaker 43: smaller scale protest
Speaker 12: movements that popped up in Iran, which they occasionally do because there's a cosmopolitan secular sort of contingent of people in Iran who don't like being ruled by an octogenarian
Speaker 12: theocrat, understandably. But Trump would do what Obama really didn't do. I mean, I don't know if you remember this, but in 2009, there was the so-called Green Revolution in Iran, where there was a big protest movement after the election of Ahmadinejad. And the Republicans were outraged that Obama didn't support that movement enough to bring about regime change. So Trump did
Speaker 12: versions of what obama was criticized for not doing on a smaller scale in the first term uh maximum pressure obviously drone striking soleimani etc so these people who
Speaker 43: thought oh we were voting for trump and we didn't realize that he was bellicose on iran like these people
are in
Speaker 43: the most ridiculous distorted
Speaker 34: information environment of all time because they only consume consume these
Speaker 34: dopey podcast where people say oh yeah trump's going to dismantle the
Speaker 43: deep state and military industrial complex and so now they're all betrayed and shocked i mean yeah
yeah
Speaker 65: it's it's true i i always thought that israel would be the one thing where trump would kind of never waver
like
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): i'm not sure trump would defend taiwan uh like we said on russia and ukraine you know he's you know he's comparable to biden at least i would say i would argue more dovish than biden but i think that this man is surrounded
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): by conservative Jews from New York, right? People who are Republican-leaning Jewish and from New York,
my
Speaker 65: God, those people. That's Florida,
Speaker 90: which is
one and
Speaker 90: the same,
pretty
Speaker 65: much. Yeah, exactly. Those are the people around him. So he was in New York City. He's around, he has in close
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): proximity to himself, Fox News, the New York Post, the Murdoch media empire, all his friends who are not
Speaker 72: liberals, who are not among New York elites. New York
Speaker 91: Average, Rudy Giuliani. I mean, these people who are the people who are in
Speaker 91: trump's actual like peer group yeah not some anti-establishment
Speaker 92: you know 35 year old podcaster yeah
and
Speaker 76: giuliani's not jewish but a very very pro-israel figure he's by in in
Speaker 15: in the terms of like the new york cultural milieu he's like functionally jewish right yeah these people are kind of functionally jewish
Speaker 14: by the way so i know these people yeah well yeah so the
uh
Speaker 94: and then like
Speaker 14: you have like
Speaker 12: you're from the new york metropolitan area you're like
it's it's
Speaker 12: Sometimes Italians
Speaker 29: and Jews are interchangeable. And then on top of that, his daughter marries Kushner.
Speaker 95: She
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): converts to Judaism. His children are raised as Jewish. Even intellectuals in the right, like City Journal, Manhattan Institute, not that Trump reads them or anything, but it's still kind of this environment where it's like you can never be anti-Israel, kind of the Peter Singer, the Paul
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): singer network um and so this is just like deeply embedded in trump like
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): israel is awesome big i mean apparently he's been meeting with rupert murdoch who's still going strong at like 95 ike perlmutter
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): who is this big uh jewish pro-israel uh entertainment
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): tycoon who gives him a lot of money uh mark levin mark levin yeah uh who i mean
I
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): used to listen to conservative talk radio while I was driving in the car and I would like to listen to Michael Savage
because he
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): has sort of a soothing voice even if he's kind of deranged and tyrannical and he would tell like sometimes amusing anecdotes and stuff and it wouldn't just be like hardcore partisan politics over and over again. That's what Hannity would do. But Levin, I just could never understand how anybody could listen for five
Speaker 91: minutes. He has the
most like
Speaker 91: tense, nasally sadistic
Speaker 96: hysterical voice yeah it's hard to listen to i can't i don't understand how this person he's
Speaker 97: yeah he
Speaker 65: screeches he screeches i mean it's kind of nuts uh yeah and like i've heard that he
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): goes he's got a cult following i've heard that he goes on if you get on the show i was actually almost got on levin's show for my book actually which is funny they told me that uh they levin had a
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Requested like a copy and wanted a signed copy. I guess that's what you do and that's like something very rare Well, I've heard that's you usually get on the show for that I don't know they ended up not doing it, but I heard that if you get on live in it like find your racist posts from
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): that Maybe they probably it was around that time. So maybe or maybe some insufficient loyalty to Trump or something, which is probably more likely
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): but
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): um yeah but i heard that if you get on levin like his audience on like watching sunday he like interviews an author and those books just fly off the shelves and we'll go to like the new york times
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): bestseller i was uh i was quoted once by rush
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): limbaugh on his show and
i got
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): a huge
i
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): had i wasn't listening obviously i wouldn't have known but i got a tsunami of feedback
from it
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): um what would people find when they would find
Speaker 95: your email or whatever
Speaker 2: uh yeah i got emails tweets um i think
somebody i'm
Speaker 34: trying to remember now i think somebody might have mentioned it in person actually
Speaker 14: like an older guy i just it just generally it makes a huge buzz which is why
Speaker 98: those places
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): and was it different when you got out when you got when you got on tucker did you it wasn't the same way i assume because my mind wasn't that big i got a lot of like subscribers and followers
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): but it wasn't like the biggest thing that ever happened it wasn't whenever I
Speaker 3: would be
Speaker 3: on tucker i
my dad
Speaker 12: would get a ton of feedback from like fellow like guys who are watching fox so my dad
would get my
Speaker 12: my dad
is
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): actually like uh basically a you know moderate democrat or something so he wouldn't be watching really otherwise but um people
in his like
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): peer group or friends or whatever him would feed
So my
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): dad would get more friends than I would. Obviously, people would maybe...
So
Speaker 76: I guess those old talk
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): radio, I guess Limbaugh's old audience and Levin's audience,
which I
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): guess maybe they're not, the future generations are not, they're probably dying
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): off. But I guess maybe that's like those talk radio guys are kind of a different level of cultishness. Is that it? I
just think it's a
Speaker 99: rock-solid, loyal audience.
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. People who've been listening...
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): habitually for years in the car or at work or something and
have it
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): as part of their daily routine
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): and schedule and
so yeah
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): they're they're going to be extremely influential in getting people to purchase products and whatnot yeah i
mean
Speaker 100: i've been enjoying have you been enjoying the levin uh tucker feud it seems like it's like generation you know it's a
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): generation x versus boomer thing uh where it's like you know levin is just completely like you know still in the old early 2000s kind of mode,
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): And
Speaker 101 (lower-pitched voice): Tucker is kind of anti-war and bitter and kind of conspiratorial. I mean, it's kind of fun to watch them, to watch them fight.
Speaker 102: Yeah. The
clip, the clip of
Speaker 103: Tucker with Ted Cruz. Yeah. What
do you
Speaker 103: think of that? I
Speaker 14: mean, I thought that was fantastic, actually. I mean, that's a perfect question to
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): ask. And that's what those sorts of questions
are not
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): asked nearly enough. I do think politicians, especially if they're going to be claiming to somehow dictate the government's
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): by force of countries on the other side of the world if they don't know basic demographic information about the country then that is
Speaker 96: humiliating particularly for
Ted Cruz
Speaker 96: Ted Cruz has been an Iran obsessive for like 15
years
Yeah.
Speaker 104: You know, it reminds me, I used to know all about this, but the run up to Iraq, I think there was a time when
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): someone basically said they talked to George Bush and he didn't know that there were Sunnis and Shia in Iraq. He basically said, what are you talking about? I thought they're all Muslims. And this was like, it was like months before.
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): The actual invasion. And so like, yeah, that's normal. I think a lot of people in Iraq, in America who ended up going toward Iraq, they probably had no idea there were Sunnis and Shia. That's like kind of like that became the basis of like the split that like was the civil war. That was like the cleavage.
in
Speaker 106: Iraqi society. So it's kind of nuts that they didn't know that. I mean, that just kind of always blew my mind. And
Speaker 34: it's not just like, I mean, I was actually a little bit surprised that Ted Cruz didn't know that. I wouldn't be surprised if some generic Republican who's... I
Speaker 107: would have liked to see him forced to guess because he might have known, but just like didn't want to... He didn't want, in case he was wrong...
Speaker 107: Well, he
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): couldn't even give, like, a rough approximation, I found. Yeah,
Speaker 30: but that's, like, he was probably, yeah, I guess. You know, I would have said, like, I would have said 80, because last time, so these countries, these third-world countries, they're always growing. Like, Iraq was
Speaker 108: 25 when we invaded, or 20, and then I didn't look for years, and then, like, 10 years later, I looked up, like, Iraq's population. If you're
Speaker 109: going to engage in, like, a new round of regime change agitation, maybe you'd, like, scan the Wikipedia or something.
Speaker 108: Yeah.
Speaker 108: Yeah, the ethnic groups is interesting, because it's only like 55% or 60% Persian, which
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): is like an interesting fact to know, you know, the Zeres are the second, like what are they kind of like, what do they think, what do they care about, that's like also kind of something you might be interested in knowing, but no, these people don't know. Yeah, there
Speaker 110: was a shocking story, it was actually like, it was around 2010 or something, 2010.
Speaker 110: 14, I don't know, that was 15, whatever, somewhere in that
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): range, which in the New York Times where they went to, so this is after the Sunni and Shia thing was like with Bush was before the Iraq war.
This is
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): like 10 years into the war on terror. And they go to Republicans on the homeland, like it was like some kind of committee, National Security Committee and Congress, they go to Republicans or maybe Republicans and Democrats and they ask him like, is Hezbollah a Sunni or Shia? Is Al-Qaeda a Sunni?
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): sunni or shia they don't know this 10 years into the war on terror right after sunni shia split had begun like the biggest story in iraq the
Speaker 110: biggest story in american politics um they still didn't know it's only like bin laden like these people did not know this stuff and it's incredible yeah they are kind of like
i've seen
Speaker 110: people defend them online like oh like that's what your aid is supposed to know but like
Then
Speaker 110: what are you? What are you as a politician? You're nothing. I mean,
Speaker 86: again, Ted Cruz actually made this a huge fixation of his. Yeah. That
he
Speaker 12: campaigned for president on. Yeah. That he's run for Senate several times on that. He's made like a legislative priority.
Yeah.
Speaker 43: And so
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): it would be one thing if Tucker asked that question to kind of just a generic Republican congressman who is not that immersed in the issue and is just sort of instinctively supporting Trump and backing regime change.
And it's also
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): like, you know, moderate
or low intelligence,
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): but I actually think Ted Cruz is pretty intelligent. He was the solicitor general of Texas. He's argued before the Supreme Court.
And
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): so that's why I did find it
a little bit
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): surprising, but all the more welcome that Tucker brought it to the fore. Yeah. Did you see Tucker
Speaker 3: on a Steve Bannon show?
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): I've seen
Speaker 111: clips of it.
Speaker 3: Yeah. I watched the whole thing
Speaker 34: and, um,
you
Speaker 12: know, I'm a little conflicted. I do. I, I like Tucker personally still. Um, and I,
He
Speaker 12: can do good journalism as evidenced
Speaker 112: by the cruise interview clip or viewing, but the way in which he couched his position on Iran,
I think speaks to
Speaker 43: how, like, if any Republican to, despite like certain people in MAGA whining
that this
Speaker 43: isn't what I voted for, quote unquote,
It shows how
Speaker 43: feeble whatever opposition they're able to muster really will be, and probably inconsequential. Because Tucker goes out of his way to say, look, I love Donald Trump. I'm
so grateful
Speaker 43: he's
Speaker 12: president. I was
with him on
Speaker 12: election night when they announced that he won Pennsylvania. It was like one of the happiest moments I've ever witnessed, et cetera, et cetera. So he couldn't have bent over backwards harder than...
to
Speaker 12: butter up trump and then of course he leads into and yet i worry
about
Speaker 43: another war in the et cetera but and even that was enough to instigate trump into attacking tucker on social so there's
Speaker 114: not going
Speaker 43: to be any like what if tucker's in a unique position if he did
want to
Speaker 43: go full anti-trump he could do so probably and have a big platform
Speaker 37: Yeah, he's
Speaker 43: like sui generis, almost most Republicans, if they want to have any hope, especially if they want to be in elective office, if they want to have any hope
of winning
Speaker 43: a Republican primary, if they want to be in these like Trump adjacent media circles or professional class circles, they can't.
Speaker 43: They might be able to gesture ancillarily at some criticisms they might have of regime change, wars in the abstract, but they can never directly criticize Trump.
Even Tucker's
Speaker 43: tack is more like, oh, I think Trump might be misled
by the
Speaker 43: people around him. So like 10 years into Trump as a national political figure, he's still constantly being manipulated by Trump.
Speaker 43: netanyahu hark levin or i don't know who is it now it used to be mike waltz that's gone who is it rubio i thought rubio was based
Speaker 14: like they never can figure out who's always chronically manipulating or tricking trump it's never about him as the primary agent of responsibility and i
Speaker 115: think it's the critique feeble and inconsequential yeah
i
Speaker 116: mean there is this like more trump than trump phenomenon where it's like tucker
Speaker 117: does this but bannon
has
Speaker 117: like really grabbed this lane and if bannon runs for president it'll be on this where it's like you continue to worship trump even bannon says trump is going to be president for a third term like you know constitution doesn't matter term limits don't matter guaranteed yeah whatever guaranteed it forecast yeah exactly but then at the same time he like will criticize trump more than a lot of people on like substance so it's like grab onto the cult of personality uh but like actually substantively differ with with trump uh which is kind
Speaker 119: of
Speaker 119: interesting and maybe it works it's never a direct criticism of trump yeah yeah
Speaker 65: how a trump is being done wrong by yeah of course no no it's weird it's a worship of trump plus like an independent like it's like always criticizing trump's decisions but like worship trump and that's
Speaker 34: like kind of the core trump is in the lineage of washington it's washington lincoln and trump so that's
it
Speaker 34: load star i
Speaker 120: think trump is beyond washington and lincoln i mean i don't know about
Speaker 72: well i don't know if washington lincoln what bannon actually explicitly says is that trump is in the washington lincoln okay then we'll take his word we'll take his word for that then they're all then they're all in the in terms of like in
Speaker 121: terms of like seismic generational civilizational
Speaker 65: yeah and so it's going to be interesting i think bannon probably you know i think he's got this lane and
Speaker 65: There's no lane to be
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): anti-Trump. If Bannon was the same but said Trump can't run for a third term and Trump is like a fool, like Bannon's audience would go away. So it
Speaker 65: is like kind of this thing because Trump's like Trump fans often don't know much about policy. So like you can manipulate them in this way. You can just tell them things that are not true or don't make sense. And then I think this is like the real like.
you
Speaker 65: know, ideological thing. And I think if Bannon runs for president in,
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): uh, 20, 28, he is like, he's going to try to have this lane, which is like Trump did all these things wrong. Not because Trump is bad. Trump is great, but like somebody manipulated him or somebody tricked him or something. And like, we are like actually with the base and a lot of like right wing, like MAGA intellectuals will like this. They'll be like the same thing. They will be like pro Trump, but then like actually like into this America first and this kind of soft white nationalist, uh, ideology.
And
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): that could be like, I don't know, that's like a powerful force. That's going to be like the battle versus like the purists, like the Trumps who are like, Trump was great and everything Trump did was great. And then, but the other side is going to be like, Trump was kind of wrong because he was manipulated. And I think those people are probably at an advantage because that's more where the base, like the base just cares about Trump himself, but like they are more policy wise with Bannon than they are with somebody like,
I
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): don't know, Rubio, before he became Secretary of State.
Speaker 122: Sometimes there are misconceptions about what the base quote-unquote
Speaker 12: consists of. Why is the base only regular viewers of the War Room Rumble show? Is it not like Fox News viewers? I think that those people
Speaker 65: are more easily... I think the energy... Okay, I showed that poll showing that
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): 72% to 19% people who support Trump wanted to help Israel in the world with Iran. So, okay, yeah, they're a majority. But
Speaker 1: it's like...
Speaker 1: I think that's seen as like a passive majority, while the minority is the minority of people who are like anti-war.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): It's all skewed dramatically by the online ecosystem that you and I are both probably over. But those are the kind of
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): people who end up shifting policy. That's what I'm saying. It's like those people who are watching Fox are going to die off. The people who are staffers in Washington and are like running like big social media accounts. And the people with the momentum on their side. And they're pushy and they're kind of aggressive and they
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): know what they want. I think the trajectory is in their favor.
Speaker 125: Possibly I just think that there's like To
Speaker 12: me that there's something Insubstantial about it Or somewhat
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): fallacious about it If this convoluted reasoning I mean,
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): tortured reasoning constantly has to be done where Trump is absolved of the
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): primary responsibility for anything that goes wrong or anything that they don't like or any out adverse
Speaker 12: consequences of anything that happens in his tenure.
And I just
Speaker 12: don't think that that adds up to like a coherent program. Like if you're constantly having
to balance
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): valorizing Trump. Yeah.
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): The question
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): is when Trump is gone, because when Trump is gone, you're not going to have to keep doing that. You're going to have a story. He's
Speaker 126: not going to be really gone, but you don't think he's going to be politically
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): active? He's going to be like 83, who knows who's going to be controlling his social account at that time, how coherent he's going to be.
Speaker 76: You don't think he's commentating on events? I think he's going to be focusing on trying to pump his meme
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): coin and going through various scams. I don't think he's going to be caring that much about politics.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): policy. Um, he's going to care about like naming buildings after him and not being prosecuted and not having like people come. I think he becomes completely kind of checked out ideologically, but it's still like a big deal. Kind of happen in
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): four years. I mean, there could be world war three and then everything that we say right now. I'm not sure that Bannon prop. I wouldn't expect Bannon to run. I would expect him to like find a candidate for him to, that he, he can rally around and, like,
be the...
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): brain of or the Vangali form. Who
Speaker 30: would that be? He's going to overshadow anyone except Vance.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): He'll overshadow any candidate. Maybe
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): it'll be Vance. Why
Speaker 127: not? Well, then it's just Vance.
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): Then it's Bannon's nothing special about Bannon. He's just the vice president
Speaker 118: becoming the successor. Bannon
is comfortable hosting
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): his podcast. I mean, I think that...
And that
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): is a good enough degree of influence for him. And people are
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): constantly asking him to interpret everything that's going on in the Republican Party and the Trump administration. So I don't know that he would necessarily personally run for president. Although, who knows?
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): You know, one point I was thinking of that I didn't get to quite finish is that you said Trump is surrounded by New
York Jews or
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): South Florida Jews or whatever.
That is
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): true enough. However, I think an under-recognized or appreciated element of Trump's posture toward Israel, both
in the
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): first term and currently, is
that if he
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): were just sort
of carrying
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): forth the preferences of that New York or South Florida Jewish set, it would be more of a conventional program.
Like
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): those people would probably comprise the mainline consensus such as it exists of the pro-Israel lobby. However, what Trump has done
that
Speaker 12: is sort of unusual and underappreciated is that he's elevated elements of.
pro-israel
Speaker 12: elements that are much more fanatical
Speaker 72: than would have been seen as kuth like 10 or 15 years ago for for republicans for republican
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): jews i don't think so like republican i think he's like right where they are like i don't think like republican jews are like you know dovish or maybe
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): well think of like what the general pro-israel consensus among
Speaker 12: the pro-israel lobby
Speaker 12: or jewish lobby to the set that existed like 10 or 15 years ago it wouldn't really have included elevating people like a ben gavir or a smotrich those people
Speaker 43: would have actually been seen as somewhat disadvantageous to the public image of pro-israel position in an american context because they're genuine messianic fanatical elements netanyahu
Kept in
Speaker 12: arm's distance from those people for many years until politically necessary for him to incorporate them into his governing
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): coalition. And you certainly wouldn't have had like secular or maybe even, you know, mildly religious pro-Israel Jews in South Florida.
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): joining
Speaker 12: hands or amplifying or elevating these hardcore evangelical apocalyptic Christian elements. They might have tolerated them or whatever, but to appoint one of them as the
Speaker 43: U.S. ambassador to Israel? I mean, Mike Huckabee literally believes in any theology that's centered around Jerusalem as the site of a final...
Gog
Speaker 43: and Magog biblical war
Speaker 29: Right, well they had to do politics
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): So I think there's two things here There's Israeli politics, you talk about Dan Yahu's Relationship with these far right people Yeah, there's that That's like moved in a certain Direction, I think the U.S. Like
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): the right Wing of the Zionist movement in the U.S. Is just basically, they're not paying that close Attention to like internal Israeli politics They're just like whatever the Israeli Whatever is pro-Israel at the time
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): That's what we're going to be. Right. And so that's why, like, Israel had moved to the right. And these people, I think, are just like
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): whatever's whatever's in the Overton window of like what's acceptable within Israel.
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): But Trump has host, for example, in July of 2023, he hosted at his Bedminster, New Jersey golf club.
a
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): fundraiser for an organization called the Israel heritage foundation or some like generic sounding name. I can't quite remember, but basically it was hardcore religious messianic fanatics who have their own little fledgling advocacy organization. And they gave
Speaker 12: Trump their big like savior of juice Jerusalem award. And he was,
Speaker 12: expressed policy affinities with them and elevated them
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): beyond what, like, a John McCain would have done, even though he was obviously pro-Israel,
or a
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Mitt Romney, or a George W.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Bush. Well, because they would have been to the right of, they would have been to the right of the right-wing people in Israel. So that's like, that would be kind of weird,
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): right? So they're just, they're just the right of America is just globbing on to whatever the most right-wing thing in Israel is. Right, and Trump is, like,
Speaker 130: tolerant or an enabler of that.
Speaker 131: Yeah, I think that's
Speaker 43: right.
Speaker 43: Trump himself, nobody really would believe,
has an
Speaker 43: ideological commitment to, quote, Zionism.
He
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): wouldn't do what Joe Biden did and go on some late-night talk show and say, I've always
Speaker 43: been a Zionist since I met Golda Meir in 1973 or whatever it was. And yet, because of his transactionalism and maybe cynicism, he does elevate these much more fanatical elements that would have been
seen as
Speaker 43: acceptable even within more mainstream republican circles like 10 or 15 years ago and how has that been made manifest well what was first what was trump's very first foreign policy proposal of his second administration first week of february netanyahu is the first foreign leader to visit the white house trump seemingly out of the blue comes out and says oh by the way the uh,
and
Speaker 43: turn it into some kind of
Speaker 34: U.S. military protectorate and expel Palestinians, that's a view that Netanyahu wouldn't have even embraced a year ago. That's the messianic
Speaker 43: settler vision within Israel that maybe has crossover with certain apocalyptic evangelical Christian elements of the United States, and that's the policy proposal. So that's Trump going beyond the conventional pro-Israel consensus in a much more fanatical
way.
Speaker 43: direction yeah
yeah i think
Speaker 30: that's
Speaker 1: right and i think that's just kind of trump's instincts i think there's these cycles that are reinforcing right it's like this
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): cycle where it's like uh this feedback loop where it's like oh the israelis are going to the right like leftists like protest against israel they protest for gaza trump
has like
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): these people who are naturally inclined towards israel supporting israel he's got these like jewish relatives and friends and acquaintances, and Trump's thing
is always
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): like, take the most
extreme
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): position as like a rhetorical device, right? And go with that. I think, yeah, all that together gives you a very, very, very pro-Israel American foreign policy, yeah. But it's
a
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): rhetorical device, right? A lot of people dismiss it at the time as just a negotiating ploy. Well, he
Speaker 127: didn't actually create a hotel in Gaza. Well,
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): not yet, but...
So
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Netanyahu and the Israeli governing coalition
Speaker 43: incorporated Trump's plan into their own war planning in Gaza. They said that a fundamental new condition for achieving what they consider to be victory in Gaza is to achieve Trump's
Speaker 12: plan. So it has a more tangible part of Trump's plan that that's expelling the Palestinians.
Yeah,
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): expelling all the Palestinians from Gaza and taking it over as a U.S. military protectorate. Wait, that's the Israeli
Speaker 76: policy as the U.S. takes it over? Yeah, implementing Trump's plan. How official is
Speaker 133: this? That's
what they
Speaker 14: proclaimed when they launched this latest phase of the Gaza offensive. It was as of early May. The goal is, the explicit goal is for the U.S. to be able to. A
couple
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): of goals, like dismantle Hamas, which was always the goal since October of 2023.
Speaker 12: xyz and then they added a new goal which is implement trump's plan
does
Speaker 134: it just say trump's plan how do they
word it um i
Speaker 135: could find the official statement i'd be
Speaker 71: interested but this is worth looking
up let's see trump plan
Speaker 136: gaza let's
see if
Speaker 136: i go quicker
Speaker 78: there's the Wikipedia page Arab counterproposal reactions, so here's
Speaker 83 (lower-pitched voice): reactions Israel Trump's plan was with Benjamin Netanyahu he said he was committed to realization of a plan rejecting Palestinian Authority Hamas governance of Gaza Netanyahu
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): says we want to ensure that Trump's plan quote, we want to ensure that Trump's plan, my edition, comes to fruition
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): It's
a
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): brilliant plan, so correct, so revolutionary.
Speaker 137: What's the date on that story?
That was
Speaker 138: May 22nd. Okay, so May 22nd.
It
Speaker 112: was announced in a coalition statement
like a week or
Speaker 112: two before, which I'm trying to find out.
Speaker 83 (lower-pitched voice): Okay, yeah, send me this link. Yeah, I see this on Wikipedia, him saying that in like February, which could be just him like, you know, in the moment, kissing up the Trump,
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): but it seems like he was still...
No, it
Speaker 139: was more than that. It was more like codified than that. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): interesting. Okay, so this is,
yeah,
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, Michael, I learned a lot. You are knowledgeable about foreign affairs. I learned a lot. Thank
Speaker 140: you. Thank you.
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): Okay. Anything else you
Speaker 12: want to? So just to wrap up, so like on Iran, are you like
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): out there agitating for regime change or like what's your position? Yeah,
Speaker 82: I mean, I think the diplomacy.
Speaker 141: Isolationists or do you actually believe that that's a good idea?
I
Speaker 65: think diplomacy could actually work in, like, the Obama-Ben Rhodes
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): kind of—I think that was working. At the same time, I don't think Israel is going to accept it, and I don't think America is going to accept it, at least, you know, this administration. And so, like, what are we going to do? Are we just going to have this kind of permanent state where it's, like, nobody, you know, kind of, like—
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): iran is kind of a hostile power and nothing ever changes within iran i think that the
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): israeli strikes on hezbollah worked out so well um that you know there's a there's a there's a possibility that you just kind of bomb iran uh you pursue the policy of regime change the country the government falls there's or there's a civil war or something and you
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): get something better in the long run i think that's kind of the answer out of all of this i don't see any other
way
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Really? So you don't see any negative ramifications or detrimental consequences of a country of 90 million, which we now don't have the population size of, descending into civil war or ethnic conflict and the state collapsing? Yeah,
Speaker 65: that's potentially bad. I mean, but like, what, should countries
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): that are ruled by brutal dictatorships stay in power forever and you should always worry about what's going to come after? You
Speaker 65: don't want to just...
Speaker 65: Like, I think it really does depend on
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): why is it your role or the role of some like congressman from Georgia to determine, OK, you know, it's time for
Speaker 29: this government to no longer continue. Because some of us see ourselves as global citizens who take the interest
Speaker 142: of the entire world
Speaker 29: into
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): account. And yeah, I think that we should care about other countries. I think it's, I think Iran, it's not Iraq where like the only opposition to Saddam was Sunni and Shia Islamists.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): Iran has a secular middle-class population that's willing to die in large numbers. Hundreds have died in these protests and tens of thousands were arrested in the last one. So it's not like a small faction within
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): Iran wants something different. And so it's a better situation than Syria. And look, things work out badly when a government falls, but sometimes things work out great, like the fall of the Soviet Union. In the end, that was better than what
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): came before. - Yeah, I think we should
probably
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): I think we should pursue a policy regime change. I think there's no reason not to, in the sense that this is a good candidate for that, given all the other countries in the world. Well,
I mean, the
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): fall of the Soviet Union was not necessarily a glorious time for a lot of the people who actually lived in the Soviet states. Sure, but
it was
Speaker 143: worth it in the long run, I think, for everyone, for most people.
Speaker 143: Poland is, like, on its
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): way to being a first-world country. Hungary, you know, all these countries have seen massive economic growth. Like, you're doubtful that the fall of the Soviet Union
Speaker 72: was on net plus?
Well, the standard
Speaker 72: of living in Russia in the 1990s was much worse. Yeah, it dipped for a few years. It dipped
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): for, like, a decade, yeah. And then it, I mean, went back up, yeah.
So, I
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): mean...
So if
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): somebody is dying of malnutrition on the street as the government
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): was changed, are they not somebody to be asked to weigh in on whether they find? Yeah,
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): somebody like obviously someone is going to be worse off of like every policy.
That
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): you pursue, right? You could be like, oh,
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): the person who the Iranian regime is going to arrest and put in jail. Like, you don't care about that person. To that person, they just want, you know, the government gone. Like, yeah, I mean, obviously.
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Okay, even if you do favor regime change in Iran or regime collapse or whatever, the Ayatollah is 86 years old. He's looking more and more pathetic and
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): feeble, actually, just like ranting and raving and having whoever posts for him on X post these, like...
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): threats that the zionists are going to be bitter that they ever
messed with iran and whatever
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): and they never it doesn't seem to amount to much i mean iran's state capacity obviously
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): has been degraded the president of iran last year was killed in a helicopter crash that was attributed to inclement weather which i still find odd but are you
Speaker 146: saying that they might fall anyway
Speaker 147: Well, I mean,
Speaker 3: he's 86, and they don't have, as far as I know, I mean, correct me if I'm wrong, if you know, is there an appointed or known successor to...
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): There are candidates. I mean, there's like two or three, but
Speaker 86: they're all the same. They're
Speaker 148: like old
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): bearded guys who are going
to
Speaker 149: be just the same thing. If
you want a
Speaker 14: more secularized government or you want like a gradual transition to a government that's more responsive to popular will,
Speaker 43: then it seems like that could be in the off end relatively soon, like maybe not...
To
Speaker 43: the dramatic extreme of the entire state apparatus being exploded into oblivion, but maybe with less downside risk than just, like, collapsing the
Speaker 86: entire state. So, I think
Speaker 65: that, like, I think that is...
You
Speaker 65: know, I think that that's easy. The
Speaker 14: morality police doesn't even doesn't enforce
Speaker 35: aggressively like the women hijab law and so forth. But
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): regimes can be decrepit and they can be failures and they can have a lot of protests for a very, very long time. So
Speaker 65: like, yeah, maybe if they're like actually weak, maybe what they actually need.
Speaker 65: is to be pushed over like you know the like there's a role potentially to play here um from the outside i don't think
Speaker 43: it's inevitable about the welfare or the aspirations of the iranian people that's not why they're doing this
i
Speaker 76: know oh i didn't say
Speaker 150: they know they don't care
Speaker 52: about because they want because iran is the one bulwark against u.s israeli hegemony in the middle east
Speaker 34: what is like is is uh saudi arabia and qatar and egypt no
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): yeah i mean you you you you asked me you asked me for you asked me for my opinion not like the motivations
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): of what uh trump and whitkoff are are up to um
So
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): your quote is about enabling the best selves of the Iranian people by bombing them. Yes,
the
Speaker 32 (lower-pitched voice): beautiful women, to free the Iranian women who are inspiring us with their courage in 2019 and 2022.
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): This is something that I think humanity has a stake in. You think Trump and
Speaker 12: the MAGA movement—
Speaker 151: Do they care? No. You're
Speaker 12: constantly railing against the
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): Trump and the MAGA
Speaker 12: movement as
like—
Speaker 12: idiots who are elevating low IQ political rhetoric and political thought. And yet now you think that they are smart enough to engineer a satisfactory
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): overthrow of the Iranian government and of a new one.
They
Speaker 65: well, it's not if they had to micromanage the process. Sure, that would be probably not a great, probably not a great plan. But they, you know, they they bumble around and do stuff that's good.
Speaker 65: pretty often. So you think that
Speaker 43: the U.S. is going to be party to the destruction of government and then just wash its hands of the situation?
Speaker 65: Oh, yeah. That's what we did. We did that in Libya. We did that in Libya. We didn't send ground troops into Libya. I mean, like, I think ground troops is a very,
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): very distant possibility in this case. It was weird for, like, we had Afghanistan, which we went into after 9-11.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): Iraq was like a very weird thing that, like, was still on the heels of 9/11. It was still like a year and a half between 9/11 and the
Iraq
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): war. And people thought that they were getting revenge for 9-11. Polls showed 70% of Americans thought Saddam basically did 9-11. And so it was very, very unusual for us to
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): send large numbers of troops willing to die in large numbers. I don't think there's any political will for that within MAGA, within anyone else. That's why these people like Bannon types keep saying, oh, all our young soldiers are going to be dying in this war, because that's the way
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): they sell it. Trump gets it.
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): that nobody's going to put up with that. So I really, really discount the possibility that we are going to be occupying Iran anytime soon. And so given that, like the question is,
what are we going to
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): do? Yeah, I mean,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): I'm not suggesting a large-scale occupation, but obviously, even in the case of Libya, the U.S. still had some tangential involvement
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): in how the governments there, the rival governments reconstituted themselves through various strategies
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): You know, a sure diplomatic efforts and so forth. So it's not as though the U.S. will be strictly uninvolved in every respect in how some forthcoming
Speaker 70: Iranian government reconstitutes. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 134: And I don't
think I
Speaker 134: don't think I don't think they need to be. I don't think they should or
Speaker 29: they would. I agree that the thing is kind of
Speaker 14: like a red herring. And in fact, it's being used by like Charlie Kirk and people as we speak to say Trump has been consistent. He doesn't want regime change wars. He doesn't want to he doesn't want endless wars. but this one is good
Speaker 14: Because it's different. It's not like what Bush
Speaker 12: did or something. And so if you're bombing Iran and it doesn't entail an immediate large-scale
Speaker 115: troop deployment, that's like within the America First ring.
Speaker 153: Well, I mean, yeah, Bush's policies were really extreme. And nobody in MAGA is
Speaker 65: like, you know, advocating. It was like, we go in, we like build the schools, like literally U.S.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): soldiers put the bricks down. I mean, you watch
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): these videos of like what they were doing in iraq you read these stories they're kind of crazy but like nobody is advocating that in iran nobody's advocating that
Speaker 65: anywhere uh right it's
Speaker 86: like we like gaza well yeah gaza how is that not nation building i mean yeah we take over gaza
Speaker 148: trump advocated that in gaza went
Speaker 43: to saudi arabia and gave that speech that some like millennial staffer probably wrote for him where
Speaker 109: he decries neocons and nation building and interventionalism I don't know why he said interventionalism rather than interventionalism.
I
Speaker 154: think you have to
Speaker 154: And
Speaker 109: then I'm initially calling for a huge nation building project in Gaza. Nobody knows the contradiction. And now they're all betrayed because we're bombing Iran.
Speaker 155: Yeah. Yeah. You know, anyways, I mean, take take the policy holistically. Take Trump's like outlook holistically. Right. You have this one
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): thing about Gaza, the U.S. taking over Gaza, which I don't think is realistic. Besides that, like, I think that there's like basically no hint of like Paul Bremer and the coalition provisional authority. Like, I don't think that's like on the table. So we can debate other things.
Speaker 21 (lower-pitched voice): like the administration might do it, whether they're a good idea or not. I think this is kind of like attacking, just like the world war three thing. I don't think is real. Like, Oh, China and Russia are going to be like, you
Speaker 156: guys try to overthrow Iran. We're, you know, we're going to nuclear war with you. Like, I don't think that's realistic either. Here's
a
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): scenario for you because I mean, there are reports that like within the next day or 48 hours or something, the U S could
Speaker 157: be joining. So here's
a
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): potential scenario.
The
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): U.S. joins Israel in offensive operations. They try to bomb the Fordow nuclear facility, and it's unclear whether the nuclear facilities are fully wiped out or the enrichment capacity is fully wiped out. Maybe it's even claimed that there's some other secret facility, like there was an intelligence leak to Fox News that's not working.
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): verified i don't think anything credible earlier this week that there was some other secret facility that iran was enriching uranium at let's say the
iranian government gets incredibly
Speaker 43: destabilized it's on the verge of collapse from follows through on his
threat to
Speaker 43: assassinate komani i mean the
Speaker 43: the extremism of trump's threats these past 48 hours is insane he's ordering mass evacuations of all of tehran 10 million people he's unconditional surrender which is what franklin roosevelt called for from the actual powers in 1943 he's uh saying he's going to uh getting ready to assassinate
the
Speaker 43: supreme leader and like meanwhile he was in michigan in october of last year telling these idiot imams that together we'll bring peace to the middle east areas but let's say like there's genuine regime destabilization it's on the verge of collapse and some
of these
Speaker 43: enrichment
Speaker 34: capacities are seized by like a rogue actor within the government or they're
Speaker 34: they're in some kind of unstable situation where some element gains control of them. Are the U.S.
Speaker 43: and Israel going to allow for some uncontrolled proliferation of nuclear technologies or something? Wouldn't that be an impetus that's cited for why there needs to be some ground element, not an Iraq-scale thing necessarily, but some incursion?
I'm
Speaker 159: not an expert in nuclear weapons development, but I think that like
Speaker 101 (lower-pitched voice): trying to build it under conditions of like civil war and like Iran, like U.S. and Israel kind of sending drones and like wiping you out and like hiding it from the world and like not being taken out. Like it's obviously like it requires some deception for Iran to do that as a functioning state.
Speaker 101 (lower-pitched voice): Whether some warlord who's a descendant of the regime can do that, I don't know if that's a
Speaker 160: reasonable possibility. I would guess probably not.
Speaker 35: I'm just speculating about some
Speaker 91: theoretical scenario that
might be used
Speaker 91: to call for...
Speaker 91: some sort of yeah i
Speaker 161: mean yeah it's interesting that's an interesting thought experiment yeah what kind of air airstrikes
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): yeah what kind of scenario
Speaker 76: would actually
Speaker 162: lead to
Speaker 76: there's got to be
Speaker 43: some of those scenarios right i mean they're not they could they're not the most unlikely outcome given how chaotic and unpredictable a regime stabilization i think
i
Speaker 100: think nukes is pretty much the only i mean it has to be that scenario right like if a lot of people are dying in a civil war.
Speaker 163: That's not, I mean, that doesn't bring the U.S. into Syria, troops on the,
boots on the
Speaker 163: ground at least um
Speaker 91: yeah wmd thing it would be dubbed something wmd related
Speaker 100: yeah i mean is that is that is that going to be a bigger threat with like iran falling apart than having the government we have now like what if you stop now what
Speaker 86: does the government do
like how
Speaker 86: do you just don't like try to why they have to go full but this is why it seems almost ineluctable
Speaker 86: It would be genuine if Trump is
up
Speaker 43: now, why wouldn't Iran rush as fast as they can to actually develop the nuclear
Speaker 164: weapon
that they
Speaker 164: apparently didn't have?
Yeah, I
Speaker 165: mean, maybe they're. Yeah, right. Like.
It would
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): be very weird. Like, we're going to release this podcast like within like an hour or two after we're done. We could
Speaker 166: get an alert. Like, I've been waiting the last day and a half like an alert anytime on my phone saying that we're going to
Speaker 155: work.
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): It's not the most healthy thing.
Speaker 155: I'm like, yeah, but if like, yeah, if 24, so I just, I did look at the prediction markets.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): It gave a 63% chance by the end of the month that the U.S. would strike Iran. It would be weird after all this stuff. Now
he can
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): get away with it because everything with
Speaker 155: him is art.
Speaker 155: of the deal. So he could change his mind whenever. But yeah, it's kind of a lot
Speaker 15: of building. Yeah, bombing Iran and imposing regime change is just like acquiring the Wollman Rink in Central Park in
Speaker 24 (lower-pitched voice): 1986, which is the main case study in the Art of the Deal. That's the new Talmud for everybody who wants to understand what the U.S. government is doing. Yeah.
Anyways,
Speaker 76: by the
Speaker 167: time people listen
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): to this, we might be at work. What's that?
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): I thought, aren't people listening live? No, they are listening live, but then we've been doing this for how long? You still don't know the routine? Yeah. And then I released it as a podcast. Oh, okay. Yeah. I knew that.
All
Speaker 169: right, then. All
Speaker 46 (lower-pitched voice): right. Well, Michael, good talking to you. And yeah, next time we talk, we may be at war. All righty. Looking forward to it. All right. Bye.